<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science Portfolio on Alina Dovhalevska</title>
    <link>https://d0vhalevska.github.io./alina_portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science Portfolio on Alina Dovhalevska</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://d0vhalevska.github.io./alina_portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://d0vhalevska.github.io./alina_portfolio/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d0vhalevska.github.io./alina_portfolio/about/</guid>
      <description>My academic journey has equipped me with a solid foundation in software engineering and a deep theoretical understanding of computer science. I have hands-on experience in working with data and employing various data analysis techniques. I am actively seeking a full-time position as a Data Scientist or Data Analyst, starting from September 2023.
Education B.Sc. in Computer Science
Technische Universität Berlin, Germany Graduated: 2018 – 2023 M.A. in Translation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis on trends regarding the most-played games</title>
      <link>https://d0vhalevska.github.io./alina_portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d0vhalevska.github.io./alina_portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>With the bloom of global economics and the fast improvement of technology, not only children but also many adults consider playing video games on their computers as one of primary ways of entertainment and are willing to invest their time and money in it, so it’s no surprise that many companies want a piece of the gaming market, especially the market of PC gaming. Despite the growing competition in this field, a good choice of genres and a wise pick of release price can still make a PC game successful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis on weather in Berlin over the years</title>
      <link>https://d0vhalevska.github.io./alina_portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d0vhalevska.github.io./alina_portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>The project involved data cleaning, manipulation, merging, and visualization using Python&amp;rsquo;s pandas and seaborn libraries. It aimed to gain insights into temperature and humidity patterns in Berlin over various years.
Results Concatenating Data
Read temperature data for the years 1980, 1990, 2000, and 2010. Concatenated the data into a single dataframe.
Groupby by Multiple Variables
Calculated the average temperature per month and year using a groupby operation on multiple columns. Examined the resulting dataframe&amp;rsquo;s index object and reseted it to integers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
